Guide to the Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Records and Photographs WAG.009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York Records and Photographs
Bulk, 1960-1999
1926-2009, bulk 1960s-1990s
WAG.009
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
229.0 linear feet in 229 record cartons and 1 folder
The Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York (PSC) is the union that represents faculty and professional/technical staff at CUNY. It is affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers as AFT Local 2234. This collection includes records of the union's activity in the areas of collective bargaining, representation of members in grievance proceedings, lobbying (at state and city levels), publicity, general support for public higher education, and participation in national, statewide and citywide labor bodies. In addition to records of the PSC, the collection includes records of its two predecessor organizations, the Legislative Conference of CUNY and the United Federation of College Teachers.
Professional Staff Congress/City University of New York.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The records of the Professional Staff Congress/CUNY were donated to the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives by the PSC in 1981. The accession numbers associated with this donation are 1981.006 and 1981.009. Since then, regular additions have been made to the Tamiment Library's holdings. A large donation of material was made in 2006, when the union moved from its long-time headquarters at 25 West 43rd Street in New York City to a new location at 61 Broadway.
Access Restrictions
Series IV and VI are restricted until 2031. All other series open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Professional Staff Congress of the City University of New York (American Federation of Teachers, Local 2234) represents faculty and staff (librarians, laboratory technicians and others) in the public higher education system of New York City. The union negotiates a system-wide contract, administers grievance procedures, lobbies aggressively at both the city and state levels, and actively represents the interests of retired members.
The faculty and staff organizations at the City University of New York have had a long history, dating from the 1930s, when there were only four city colleges (Brooklyn, City, Hunter and Queens). Much of the early union work at the city colleges was done by the Legislative Conference (LC), founded in 1939 and led from 1944 by Professor Belle Zeller of Brooklyn College. The LC achieved statutory tenure in 1940 and secured some significant improvements in salaries and pensions; but it remained independent of organized labor and in many respects saw itself as a professional organization rather than a trade union. In the early 1960s, the Legislative Conference was challenged by the United Federation of College Teachers (UFCT), led by president Israel Kugler. The UFCT, originally the college teachers' local of the United Federation of Teachers, became an independent local of the American Federation of Teachers in 1963. Members of the UFCT wanted a union that would be more aggressive in pursuit of collective bargaining rights and that would be part of the AFL-CIO. In 1965-66 the UFCT won much positive publicity for its staunch defense of thirty-one faculty members of St. John's University who were dismissed without charges being brought against them. Although the St. John's "strike" was formally lost, UFCT picket lines made front-page news, and St. John's was censured by the American Association of University Professors.
In response to the challenge posed by its dynamic rival, the LC began to seek recognition as exclusive bargaining agent for CUNY faculty. The 1967 Taylor Law, granting public employees in New York State the right to choose a collective bargaining agent, heightened the competition for faculty allegiance, and paved the way for a referendum on the issue. In general senior faculty were inclined to support the LC, while the UFCT commanded widespread support among lecturers and adjuncts.
After several years of heated negotiations and campaigning which threatened to bankrupt the two organizations, a merger between the Legislative Congress and the United Federation of College Teachers was achieved in 1972. The Professional Staff Congress (PSC), under the leadership of president Belle Zeller and deputy president Israel Kugler, became one of the first unions of college teachers to negotiate a university-wide contract. This set the pattern for college-teacher unionism throughout the country.
The PSC defeated an attempt to impose tenure quotas in 1973, rallied public support for the CUNY system during the New York City fiscal crisis of the mid-1970s and fought off budget-cutting and "restructuring" proposals aimed at limiting the provision of public higher education. After the election of Irwin Polishook as president in 1976, the union won improvements in funding for community colleges, and benefit plans (including health coverage for retirees and adjuncts) were strengthened. Recurring fiscal crises and a political climate increasingly hostile to expenditure on public higher education, have regularly forced the union into dual role, defending the gains of the past while adjusting to a changing environment.
When the PSC was formed the City University was in the midst of a momentous transformation. An open admissions policy had been instituted in 1970 and all New York City high-school graduates now had access to CUNY's four-year colleges. Many CUNY faculty members embraced open admissions as a way for the University to fulfill its mission of educating all New Yorkers. However, the "Search for Education, Elevation, and Knowledge" (SEEK) Program that was supposed to provide the necessary remediation was never adequately funded, and this made it impossible to fulfill the promise of open admission.
Veteran PSC members saw dramatic changes in the City University during their working lives. Many of them who began their careers in the 1950s and 1960s remembered a university that was highly selective and, with free tuition, educated some of the brightest students in the City of New York. The 1970s, 1980s and 1990s saw an influx of students in need of remedial work, cut-backs resulting from New York's fiscal crisis, salaries that failed to keep up with those at comparable universities, substantial cuts in full-time faculty positions and a sharp increase in adjunct faculty. The years of retrenchment, however, also brought increasing ethnic, racial and religious diversity and pressure toward gender equity. In 1983 Professor Lilia Melani won a major lawsuit that forced the University to address the issues of discrimination against women in appointments, hiring, and tenure. During the 1970s, 1980s and 1990s there were also steady increases in the numbers of African-American, Asian-American and Latino faculty members. This helped create role models for students from immigrant and minority backgrounds, who were coming to CUNY in increasing numbers.
In February 2000, Irwin Polishook retired. In the union electionof May 2000, an insurgent group, the New Caucus, defeated the caucus that had led the union since 1973. Barbara Bowen became President.
Sources:
Irwin Yellowitz, Twenty-five Years of Progress: Professional Staff Congress/CUNY (New York: Professional Staff Congress/CUNY, [1997].
Grayson, Gerald H., "Professors Unite: A History of the Legislative Conference of City University of New York." Ph.D. dissertation, New York University, 1973.
Scope and Content Note
The collection documents the Professional Staff Congress's participation in collective bargaining and grievance proceedings on behalf of its members, as well as its lobbying efforts and other political activities in support of public higher education, various labor organizations, and other causes. The collection traces the union's activities from the 1920s to the 2000s, but is particularly rich in materials from the late 1960s to the 1990s. Publicity materials, correspondence, minutes, office files of individual officers and staff members, files pertaining to benefits-related programs and committees, photographs and audiovisual materials, and the records of the PSC publication Clarion (including many photographic materials) are also present. To a lesser extent, the collection contains the records of PSC's two predecessor organizations, the United Federation of College Teachers and the Legislative Conference.
Arrangement
All series and subseries are arranged alphabetically by topic. Series VII and part of Series V, Subseries E is unprocessed.
The files are grouped into 7 series:
I. Records of the United Federation of College Teachers
II. Records of the Legislative Conference
III. Records of the Professional Staff Congress
IV. Arbitrations (CLOSED)
V. Addendum
VI. Legal Files, Arbitrations, and Grievances (CLOSED)
VII. Photographs and Audiovisual Materials
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Records of American Federation of Teachers, Local 1460 (WAG 96)
Records of the Professional Staff Congress, Kingsborough Community College Chapter (WAG 81)
Records of the Professional Staff Congress, New Caucus (WAG 94)
Records of Communications Workers of American, Local 1180 (WAG 63)
Records of the United Federation of Teachers (WAG 22)
Professional Staff Congress Oral History Collection (OH 061)
Alexander, Aaron C.; American Association of University Professors.; American Federation of Teachers. Local 2234 (New York, N.Y.).; Campbell, Claude.; City University of New York--Employees--Labor Unions.; City University of New York.; Kugler, Israel, 1917-2007; Legislative Conference of the City University of New York.; Polishook, Irwin H.; United Federation of College Teachers.; Yellowitz, Irwin.; Zeller, Belle, 1903-; College teachers' unions |z New York (State) |x History.; College teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x History.; College teachers' unions |z New York (State) |z New York |x Officials and employees.; Contracts.; Correspondence.; Minutes.; New York (N.Y.); Official reports.; Press releases.; Records (documents); Speeches.; Universities and Colleges |x Employees |x Labor Unions.
- Series I: Records of the United Federation of College Teachers, 1935-1972
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: Records of the United Federation of College Teachers, includes Executive Board minutes (1963-1972), files on individual campuses and categories of CUNY employees, correspondence, extensive files on grievances (many arranged alphabetically by name), Negotiating Committee files, mass mailings to members, publicity materials, and material relating to the new York State College and University Council of the American Federation of Teachers.
  - Constitution and Charter, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minutes: Executive Board, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Administration, undated, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administration Committee: Minutes, 1963, 1969-1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1963, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Arbitration Awards, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Audits, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baruch College, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Bronx Community College, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brooklyn College, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Chapter Manuals, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - City College, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - City College, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - City College, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - City University College Council, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - City University of New York: Librarians, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - CUNY: Librarians, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - CUNY: Science and Technical Assistants, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - CUNY: Science and Technical Assistants, 1968-1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - CUNY: Women's Coalition, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - City University Reporter, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Clippings, 1963-1972 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Collective Bargaining Elections, undated, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Committee for Registrars, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Committee on the University and the Community, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Conference, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Contracts, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Correspondence, 1964-1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence: Amalgamated Bank, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence: American Civil Liberties Union/ NY Civil Liberties Union, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence: AFL-CIO: National, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence: AFL-CIO: State, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence: AFT, 1963-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence: AFT, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence: Board of Higher Education: CUNY, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, Jan 1969-Jul 1969 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, Aug 1969-Dec 1969 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, Jan 1970-Jun 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, Jul 1970-Dec 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: BHE/CUNY, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: CUNY Student Organizations, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Empire State Federation of Teachers/United Teachers of NY, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Government Officials, 1960-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Government Officials, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Government Officials, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Honest Ballot Association, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Jewish Labor Committee, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Kaplan, D.: Attorney, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: Legislative Conference, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: NYC Central Labor Council, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence: Officers, 1963-1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Other Teacher Unions, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Periodicals, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Public Employment Relations Board, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence: PERB, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Radio and TV, undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence: United Federation of Teachers, 1967-1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence: US Labor Department, 1968-1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence: University Senate, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence: Vladeck, Elias, et al, Attorneys, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence: Vladeck, Elias, et al, Attorneys, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Educational Policy Committee, 1965-1970 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Empire State Federation of Teachers: Correspondence, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - ESFT: Minutes, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Survey, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Fashion Institute of Technology, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Finances, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 32A)
  - Governance Committee/ Subcommittee, 1969-1972 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Grievance Committee, 1967-1969 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Grievance Committee, Jan 1970-Mar 1970 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Grievance Committee, Apr 1970-May 1970 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Grievance Committee, Jun 1970-Aug 1970 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Grievance Committee, Sep 1970-Oct 1970 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Grievance Committee, Nov 1970-Dec 1970 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Grievance Committee, Jan 1971-Feb 1971 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Grievance Committee, Mar 1971-Jun 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Grievance Committee, Jul 1971-Nov 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Grievance Committee, Dec 1971-Mar 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grievance Committee, Apr 1972-Aug 1972 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Grievants A - B, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Grievants C - Deme, undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Grievants Dems - DeV, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Grievants Di - Fab, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Grievants Fac - Fe, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Grievants Fi - Ger, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Grievants Get - Greenb, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Grievants Greene - Har, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Grievants Has - Hoa, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Grievants Hof - I, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Grievants J - Kal, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Grievants Kan - Ki, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Grievants, undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Grievants L - Lesk, undated (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Grievants Less - Lo, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Grievants Lu - Ma, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Grievants Mc - Mon, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Grievants Mor - N, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Grievants O - Oro, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Grievants Ort - Pol, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Grievants Por, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Grievants Pos - Ri, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Grievants Rob, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Grievants Rod, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Grievants Ros - Ry, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Grievants S - Schr, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Grievants Schu - Se, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Grievants Sh - Sig, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Grievants Sil - So, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Grievants Sp, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Grievants St - Tal, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Grievants Tam - Thoma, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Grievants Thomp - Vi, undated (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Grievants Vo - Weis, undated (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Grievants Weit - Wil, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Grievants Wim - Z, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Hunter College, 1962-1972 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Kingsborough Community College, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Kugler, I.: Job Status, 1947, 1965-1972 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Legislative Program, 1960-1967 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Legislative Program, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Mailings and Flyers: General, 1962-1967 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Mailings and Flyers: General, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Mailings and Flyers: General, 1969-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Mailings Index, 1968-1971 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Mailings to Adjuncts, 1971-1972 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Mailings to Instructors, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Mailings to Lecturers, 1964-1972 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Mailings to Members, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Mailings to Members, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mailings to Members, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Mailings to Officers, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Mailings to Other Constituencies, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Manhattan Community College, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Member/Officer Lists, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Colleges, 1967-1972 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Nassau Community College, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Negotiating Committee, Jan 1969-Apr 1969 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Negotiating Committee, May 1969 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Negotiating Committee, Jun 1969-Dec 1969 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Negotiating Committee, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - NYC Community College, 1954-1962 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - NYC Community College, 1963-1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - NYC Community College, 1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - NYC Community College, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - NYC Community College: Vorhees Campus, 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - NY Federation of College Teachers/Teachers Guild, 1935-1943, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - NYS AFT College and University Council: Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Constitution, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 17A)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Correspondence, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Correspondence, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Correspondence: AFL-CIO, 1968-1970 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Correspondence: Replies to SUNY Position Papers, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Finances, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Mailings, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - NYS AFT CUC: Minutes, 1967-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - NYS AFT CUC PERB: Legal Issues, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - NYS AFT CUC PERB: Legal Issues, Jan 1969-Aug 1969 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - NYS AFT CUC PERB: Legal Issues, Sep 1969-Jan 1971 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - NYS AFT: Organizing, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pension Committee, 1966-1971 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Press Releases, 1962-1968 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Press Releases, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Queensborough Community College, 1968-1972 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Queensborough Community College: Science and Technical Assistants, 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - QUEST Committee, 1969-1972 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Regional Opportunity Centers, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Richmond College, 1966-1972 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Saint John's University, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - SEEK Program, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Speeches, ca.1965-1967 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Speeches, ca.1968-1971 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Speeches and Debates, 1967-1971 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Staff, 1965-1972 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - State University of New York (SUNY) Urban Center: Brooklyn, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - SUNY Urban Center: Harlem, 1969-1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Staten Island Community College, 1963-1972 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Symposium: "University and the Modern Age", 1968 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Taylor Law and Comments, 1967-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Testimony at Hearings, 1963-1968 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Testimony at Hearings, 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Union Factions and Caucuses, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Voter Analysis, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Westchester Community College, 1967-1968 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Westchester Community College, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Westchester Community College, 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Westchester Community College: Harris and Roode Cases, Mar 1969-Sep 1969 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Westchester Community College: Harris and Roode Cases, Oct 1969-Dec 1970 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Writings, 1966-1970 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Writings, 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Yeshiva University, 1966-1972 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - York College, 1967-1972 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Series II: Records of the Legislative Conference, 1926-1975
  Series II: Records of the Legislative Conference, includes minutes (1938-1972), files on individual campuses, files relating to the Board of Higher Education, documentation of relations with CUNY administrators, officers' correspondence, legislative issues files, documentation on the struggle for collective bargaining representation, files on salaries, and extensive documentation of the activities of LC president Belle Zeller.
  - Bylaws, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Bylaws, 1965, 1967, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Minutes I (Bound), Dec 1938-Oct 1955 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Minutes II (Bound), Nov 1955-May 1964 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Minutes III (Bound), Oct 1964-May 1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Minutes/Meeting Notes, Miscellaneous, 1936-1938, 1962-1972 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for City University, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Collective Bargaining, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Parity, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on the Future of the Conference, 1968-1970 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Admission of Community Colleges, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)